>> 凯尔 - 辛普森:
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Since
it was asked earlier,
让我们来讨论康斯特的问题
let's segue into a discussion of const.
最重要的是比让更多的人更清楚。
Const is by most accounts
even better than let.
您不应该使用 let ，并且只能尽可能使用常量。
You should not even use let and you
should only use const wherever possible.
所以我对 const 的问题本质上是 const 关键字
So the problem that I have with const
is essentially the const keyword
在语言中不携带自己的体重。
does not carry its own
weight within the language.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这句话有时用在规格上
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's a phrase that
is sometimes used in specifications or
标准。
standards.
有人说也许会有好处但是
When somebody says, yeah,
there might be a benefit, but
成本更高，所以不值得。
the cost is greater and
so it's not worth it.
我想说的是也许会有一点好处
And what I'm saying is, that there
might be a slight benefit to const,
这并不像你所相信的那么重要
it is not as significant as you
have been led to believe, and
我认为更重要的是要付出代价
there is a cost to const which
is in my opinion greater.
它没有自己的重量
It doesn't carry its own weight.
那不代表我没用，意思是我用的时候很麻雀，
That doesn't mean I never use it, it means
I am very sparing in when I use it and
我只在非常具体的案例中使用它。
I only use it in very specific cases.
与我的所有声明相比，这是我的一般替代。
As opposed to it's my general
replacement for all declarations.
因此， const 的大成本甚至不是 JavaScript 独有的。
So, the big cost that comes with const
is not even unique to JavaScript.
如果您立即进入 Stack Overflow 并搜索
If you go on Stack Overflow right now and
search for
const 关键字的问题，你会发现成千上万的
problems with the const keyword,
you'll find tens of thousands of
各种不同语言的帖子
posts across a whole variety
of different languages.
因为结果是每次将 const 关键字添加到任何一个
Because it turns out, every time the const
keyword has ever been added to any
编程语言程序员感到困惑
programming language,
programmers got confused.
我认为他们感到困惑的原因之一
And I think one of the reasons
they get confused,
是因为当我们想到康斯特的时候我们想到了常数
is because when we think of const,
and we think of the word constant.
我们在想的是，一个不改变的东西。
What we're thinking to ourselves is,
a thing that doesn't change.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 但这不是程序员的意思，或者
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: But that's not what
a programmer means by const, or
至少这不是编程语言设计师的意思
at least that's not what a programming
language designer means by const.
编程语言设计器表示无法重新分配的变量，
A programming language designer means
a variable that can't be reassigned,
那是两个完全不同的事情。
and those are two entirely
different things.
在这里，第 4 行，宣布一个常量，一个无法重新分配的 myTeacher 。
Here, on line 4, am declaring a const,
a myTeacher that can't be reassigned.
因此我在第 5 行上出现错误，但
So I get an error on line 5, but
当我声明一个类似于数组的可变值时会发生什么情况。
look what happens when I declare
a mutable value like an array.
我不是要在第 8 行重新分配老师所以我没有错
I'm not trying to reassign teachers
on line 8, so I get no error,
但事实上我仍在突变完全允许的价值
but I am actually still mutating
the value which is totally allowed.
这产生了各种各样的挫折感作为一个事实
This creates all kinds of frustration,
as a matter of fact,
有些语言在这方面有很大的挣扎
some languages have struggled so
much with this.
例如，例如 Java，它们已除去到常量关键字，并且
Like for example Java,
they removed to the const keyword and
放入另一个称为 final 的关键字。
put in another keyword called final.
这样他们就能把自己和别人的行李分开
Just so they could sort of separate
themselves from the baggage of people
认为这件事是不重要的
thinking that this thing meant
something that it didn't.
我不确定最终是否更好，但这就是他们所做的，好吗 ?
I'm not sure that final is better,
but that's what they did, okay?
所以有个随身携带的行李
So, there is a baggage
that comes with const.
您的代码中有新的读者，除非他们已经熟悉
And a new reader to your code unless
they are already well familiar with
const 的概念以及可变值与可变值之间的差异的概念
the concept of const, and the idea of
the difference between mutable values and
可变分配。
mutable assignments.
更有可能的是，当他们看到你说的时候，读者可能会被绊倒
It is more likely than not that a reader
could get tripped up when they see you say
我们的老师是平等的然后他们就会看到像阵列一样的东西
const teachers equals and
then they see something like an array,
他们很可能要把他们的
they are most likely takeaway
that they would get or
他们最有可能得到的印象是这个阵列不会改变
the most likely impression that they
would get is that the array won't change.
它不会改变它本身不是你在说的
That it won't mutate itself,
that's not what you were saying.
你是说不我只是不去重新分配变量
You were saying, no,
I'm just not gonna reassign the variable,
所以当你把阵列静音时，突然之间就会混淆。
so that when you mutate the array,
all of a sudden they get confused.
所以这个常量关键字有这个问题，它有这个包袱。
So the const keyword has this
problem to it, it has this baggage.
现在你应该在很小的街区内使用这个常量关键字，对吧 ?
Now, you're supposed to use the const
keyword within a very small block, right?
你应该把你的街区
You're supposed to keep
your block small and
你应该用小积木里的最重要的词
you're supposed to use the const
key word within small blocks.
从语义的角度来说， const 关键字是什么意思，
What the const keyword is actually saying,
from a semantic perspective is,
我保证它不会被重新分配的
for the rest of this block,
I promise it's not gonna get reassigned.
我不认为重新分配实际上是个大问题。
I don't think that reassignment
is actually a big problem.
这不是我的程序中常见的错误来源。
That isn't the source of bugs
typically in my program.
但即使是虫子的来源如果我用一小块
But even if it were a source of bugs, if I
use the const inside of a small block of
三到五行代码，我最能告诉用户的是，猜测是什么，
three to five lines of code, what I am
at best telling the user is, guess what,
在接下来的四列代码中我是不会重新分配的
on the next four lines of code
I'm not gonna reassign it.
Cuz 在整个程序中只有 4 行代码可以重新分配
Cuz there is only four more lines of code
in the entire program that could reassign
它，因为词法限定作用如何， >> Kyle Simpson: const 关键字
it, because of how lexical scoping works,
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: The const keyword
假装它为我们做了一件很棒的事
pretends as if it's doing this
major awesome thing for us, and
其实根本不是这么做的
it's not actually doing that much at all.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 没有解决很多问题。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Not
solving that many problems.
所以它有这个问题，不是真正解决这个问题，
So it has this problems, and
it's not really solving the problem that
它有点像你孩子卧室里的夜间照明
it pretends, it's kinda like a night
lighting in your child's bedroom.
这绝对让你的孩子觉得衣橱里没有怪物
It definitely makes your child feel better
that there's no monsters in the closet,
但我们都知道衣橱里没有怪物
but we all know there's no
monsters in the closet.
这让你感觉很好但我不确定它是否真的
So it makes you feel good, but I'm not
sure that it really is carrying its
自己的体重减轻了可能带来的困惑
own weight with the potential
of confusion that comes.
因此，所有考虑的因素，我个人的决定是我
So, all of that taken into consideration,
my personal take on const is that I
仅当我指定一个已为原语的值时使用它
only use it when I am assigning a value
that is already a primitive and
因此无法改变。
therefore immutable.
因此，我只会用字符串， Booleans 或数字之类的内容来安慰。
So I will only use const with things
like strings, Booleans, or numbers.
我用它作为那些文字的语义占位符。
And I use it as a semantic place
holder for those literals.
如果有 13 号这就意味着什么特别的
So if have the number 13, and
that means something special and
在我的节目里魔法我会给它一个特殊的魔法
magical in my program, I'll give it
the name special magical in a const
而不是只使用 13
declaration instead of just using 13.
这就是所谓的常量。
That's what constants
are supposed to be for.
它们应该赋予语义作为占位符。
They're supposed to give
semantic meaning as placeholders.
我不认为我们需要一个常量来阻止我们意外地重新分配东西。
I don't think we need a const to prevent
us from accidentally reassigning things.
我不认为这是一个大问题，至少在一般意义上。
I just don't think it's that big of
a problem, at least in the general sense.
这就是我对康斯特的意见
That's my take on const,
where many of the developers
会告诉你你应该用康斯特的
out there will tell you
that you should use const.
然后你就应该让你和你永远别用 var了
And then you should use let and
you should never use var.
我的建议已撤销，您应该缺省使用 var。
My advice is reversed,
you should default to using var.
在有用的地方使用
Use let where it is helpful,
仅将常量与 immutable 原始值一起使用。
use const sparingly only with
immutable primitive values.